Everyone wants the truth... until they find it.
Gone Baby Gone is a crime, drama, mystery film directed by Ben Affleck.
When 4 year old Amanda McCready disappears from her home and the police make little headway in solving the case,
the girl's aunt, Beatrice McCready hires two private detectives, Patrick Kenzie and Angie Gennaro.
The detectives freely admit that they have little experience with this type of case, but the family wants them
for two reasons—they're not cops and they know the tough neighborhood in which they all live.
Patrick Kenzie, played by Casey Affleck.
Angie Gennaro, played by Michelle Monaghan.
Jack Doyle, played by Morgan Freeman.
Sgt. Det. Remy Bressant, played by Ed Harris.
Det. Nick Poole, played by John Ashton.
Helene McCready, played by Amy Ryan.
Gone Baby Gone is a 2007 American neo-noir crime thriller film
directed by Ben Affleck in his directorial debut.
Affleck co-wrote the screenplay with Aaron Stockard based on the
1998 novel of the same name by Dennis Lehane.
The film stars Casey Affleck and Michelle Monaghan as two Boston private investigators hunting
for a young girl abducted from her single mother's apartment in Dorchester.
The supporting cast includes Morgan Freeman, Ed Harris, and Amy Ryan.
It was the final film to be released by The Ladd Company
before its closure on December 19, 2007.
Released on October 19, 2007, Gone Baby Gone was well-received by critics and
grossed $34 million worldwide against a $19 million budget.
Ben Affleck was lauded for his directing debut by critics, while Amy Ryan
received an Oscar nomination for Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of robbery, corruption, based
on novel or book, police, kidnapping.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.